Almas Baimagambetov

STATEMENT

I am a Senior Lecturer in Game Development at the University of Brighton, where I teach a range of computer science, software and game development modules. My PhD is in computer science and I remain an active researcher. I am the author and maintainer of FXGL, a game engine used by several academic institutions to teach game development. I lead and contribute to numerous projects on GitHub and run an educational YouTube channel covering game and software development.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Feb. 2020 - Present	Senior Lecturer in Game Development University of Brighton, UK
	University of Brighton, UK
C + 0010 I 0010	
Sept. 2018 - Jan. 2019	Lecturer in Game Development
	Lecturer in Game Development University of Brighton, UK
Oct. 2015 - Aug. 2018	Part-time Lecturer in Game Development
	Part-time Lecturer in Game Development $University \ of \ Brighton, \ UK$
Oct 2012 Feb 2015	Cuest Specker and Menter for IT students (Volunteer)
Oct. 2012 - Feb. 2015	Guest Speaker and Mentor for IT students (Volunteer) Bellerbys College, UK

EDUCATION

Feb. 2019 - Oct. 2020	PGCert in L&T HE, University of Brighton, UK
July 2015 - Dec 2019	PhD in Computer Science, University of Brighton, UK
	Thesis: automated visualization of grouped networks
	using Euler diagrams and graphs
	keywords: set theory, graph theory, topology,
	computational geometry & graphics
Oct.2012 - July 2015	BSc Computer Science (Games), University of Brighton, UK
	Final year project:
	analysis of software development issues in large scale games
	Project grade: A+ Degree: 1st Class Honours

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Check out GitHub for examples of projects.

Advanced: Java, JavaFX, Kotlin,

game engine development (ECS, AI, UI, IO, serialization, physics,

event systems, networking, scripting),

API design, TDD, FDD, DDD, CI, deployment, software development principles and practices,

algorithms and data structures

Intermediate: C++, JS, Win/Mac/Linux, LATEX

Beginner: Unity, UE4, SQL, HTML, CSS, Haskell, Python, Shell

AWARDS

Oct. 2019	CLT Scholarship (£1000), Centre of Learning & Teaching, UoB
June 2018	Best Student Paper, Diagrams 2018 Conference
Sept. 2015	International Research Scholarship (50% fee reduction), UoB
July 2015	Best Final Year Development Project (£250)
	The FDM Group Prize
Nov. 2014	Academic Merit Based Scholarship (£1000), UoB
Nov. 2013	Academic Merit Based Scholarship (£1000), UoB

RESEARCH AND PROFESSIONAL TALKS (PREV. 5 YEARS)

Telegrame in in	The I work and the state of the
February 2021	
T 0001	(FOSDEM 2021)
January 2021	A Practical Introduction to FXGL
	(Brighton Java Meetup)
November 2020	Modern JavaFX Game Development with FXGL
	(JFX-Days Conference)
August 2020	Evaluating Visualizations of Sets and Networks
	(11th International Conference on the Theory and Application of Diagrams)
July 2020	Impact of Gamified Work-based Learning on Student Experience
	(Education and Student Experience Conference)
June 2019	Automated Visualization of Grouped Networks Using Euler Diagrams and Graphs
	(CEM Conference)
April 2019	Java and JavaFX Game Development
	(Brighton Java Meetup)
June 2018	Generating Effective Euler Diagrams
	(10th International Conference on the Theory and Application of Diagrams)
May 2017	Novel Algorithm for Euler Diagram Generation
-	(University of Brighton Internal Conference)
March 2017	Data Visualization Workshop
	(Presenter at Data Visualization Brighton Meetup)
Feb. 2017	An Inductive Approach to P-preserving Euler Diagram Generation
	(Visual Modelling Group Talk)
June 2016	Grouped Networks and Associated Challenges
	(University of Brighton Internal Conference)
May 2016	Euler Diagram Generation Techniques
-J = -	(Visual Modelling Group Talk)
	()

PUBLICATIONS

- 1. **Baimagambetov, A.**, Stapleton, G., Blake, A. and Howse, J. (2020) Evaluating Visualizations of Sets and Networks that Use Euler Diagrams and Graphs In: 11th International Conference on the Theory and Application of Diagrams, Tallinn, 24-28 August 2020.
- 2. **Baimagambetov, A.**, Howse, J., Stapleton, G. and Delaney, A. (2018) Generating Effective Euler Diagrams In: 10th International Conference on the Theory and Application of Diagrams, Edinburgh, 18-22 June 2018.
- 3. **Baimagambetov**, **A.** (2018) Automated Visualization of Grouped Networks In: 10th International Conference on the Theory and Application of Diagrams, Edinburgh, 18-22 June 2018. (Graduate Symposium report).